### Matthias Mullie

Lijsterstraat 7 8550 Zwevegem, Belgium +32 472 42 89 94 matthias@mullie.eu



I'm a senior software engineer with over a decade of experience in building web applications, mostly in PHP, Python, MySQL, JavaScript & related tech. I care about code architecture.

I love hard challenges, clean code & learning new things. I firmly believe in applying the boy scout rule to code. I'm pragmatic and able to get things done. I play soccer, like to run & love traveling.

## Experience

## Senior software engineer, Wikimedia Foundation

San Francisco, CA, USA (remote) – 🐧 wikimediafoundation.org

2012 - present

Implemented many, many new features across Wikimedia projects, among which: cross-wiki notifications, discussion board, structured (meta)data for multimedia & media search.

Work ranges all across the stack, from high-level systems architecture work to low-level implementation details, interfacing with other services or building own solutions when alternatives don't work (e.g. a modern templates-based reactive frontend), from being involved in product/design to improving backend code performance.

### Lead developer, Wijs

Ghent, Belgium – ₩ wijs.be

2008 - 2012

I architected & implemented a wide variety of projects: marketing websites, e-commerce, ERP integrations, (small) social platforms, ...

I led & mentored a 6 person team to ensure shipping on time & within budget, free of issues. *Usually*:) I led the technical direction & resource allocation of open source Fork CMS & grew it to 4k+ installs/month.

# Projects & open source

**Effort** – Workout tracker/training plan app – 

effortapp.com

open source), until it generated some fancy metrics.

I've built a mobile app to monitor sports performances & suggest an adaptive training plan. There's a comprehensive API & allows syncing with 3rd party providers (such as Strava or Garmin) as well as on-device tracking.

**Cauditor** – Code metrics analyzer – **3** cauditor.org (offline; hosting cost)

I set up this AWS-hosted SaaS to generate & visualize engineering metrics for PHP projects. The website (in Python) lets you link GitHub repos. 2 SQS queues then trigger the metrics generation (in PHP &

**Scrapbook** – Transactional cache – **№** scrapbook.cash – **۞** github.com/matthiasmullie/scrapbook

I implemented a Memcached-like API for multiple cache backends, but that was just a prerequisite for the real cool stuff in here: stampede protection, sharding & transactions.

Minify – JS & CSS minifier – minifier.org – github.com/matthiasmullie/minify

How did a few regular expressions grow into this thing with 4m+ installs that I no longer want to maintain!?

### Education

#### **Bachelor in Applied Computer Science, Katho**

Kortrijk, Belgium – katho.be

2004 - 2011

ASP.NET, Java, Oracle DB, HTML, CSS, XML, Networking, OOP, ...

## PHP developer, Katho

Wevelgem, Belgium – 🔤 vdab.be

2007 - 2008

PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, XML